<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Features on Dadgum Box Scores</title>
    <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/categories/features/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Features on Dadgum Box Scores</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/categories/features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Defensive End in College Basketball</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/julius-frazier-peppers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/julius-frazier-peppers/</guid>
      <description>The Best Defensive End in College Basketball Julius Peppers enters his 18th NFL season next week. Before Peppers was an NFL superstar, he was a Tasamanian Devil of a two-sport athlete.
In the August 2001 issue of Sports Illustrated, Tim Crothers detailed the story of Peppers in a way only Crothers could do.
Peppers, a native of Bailey, N.C., was heavily recruited out of Southern Nash high school for both basketball and football.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>True or False: Freshmen</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/true-or-false-freshman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/true-or-false-freshman/</guid>
      <description>True or False: Freshmen True or False: Bobby Frasor is the only player in the Roy Williams era to start every game as a freshman.
True or False: Freshmen played a higher percentage of minutes during the 2005 Championship season than the 2009 or 2017 Championship seasons.
True or False: Nate Britt started more games as a freshman than Marvin Williams, Tony Bradley, and Danny Green combined.
True or False: A freshman has started at least one game in eight of 15 seasons in the Roy Williams era.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Retrospect, the 2017-18 Season</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/18-season-retrospect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/18-season-retrospect/</guid>
      <description>In Retrospect, the 2017-18 Season Fresh off the 2017 National Championship, North Carolina entered the 2017-18 season with a ton of uncertainty.
Carolina finished 26-11 overall, 11-7 in the ACC. The season ended in Charlotte in the second round of the NCAA Tournament.
A bit of perspective during the Roy Williams era.
After winning the 2005 National Championship, Carolina finished with a 23-8 record and its season ended in the second round of the NCAA Tournament.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duke &amp; Carolina: Early Entries</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/duke-carolina-early-entries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/duke-carolina-early-entries/</guid>
      <description>Duke &amp;amp; Carolina: NBA Early Entries Roy Williams was asked if the nature of the Duke-North Carolina rivalry has changed because of the frequent turnover of the players. Read his response below or listen to it here.
 It&amp;rsquo;s still the names of the front. You guys won&amp;rsquo;t believe this, but I think, strongly, we&amp;rsquo;ve had more guys leave early since I&amp;rsquo;ve been here than they have. Period. We just haven&amp;rsquo;t had the one-and-dones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carolina’s Frequent Fouler</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/carolinas-frequent-fouler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/carolinas-frequent-fouler/</guid>
      <description>Carolina’s Frequent Fouler Isaiah Hicks is one of the most puzzling UNC basketball players of all-time.
Because he can do things most collegiate players dream about, like putting opponents on a poster as seen here:
 But Hicks struggles to stay on the floor because he does a lot of this:
 Isaiah Hicks has committed four or more fouls in 31 of his last 70 career games. That’s 44 percent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Throw Rate since &#39;03-04</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/free-throw-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/free-throw-rate/</guid>
      <description>Where have all the free throws gone UNC looked the part of a National Champion for the majority of the 2015–16 season.
Last year’s squad had a higher adjusted offensive efficiency (123.3) and turnover rate (15.4) than both the 2005 and 2009 championship teams.
But where did the Tar Heels struggle?
A factor that gets overlooked is getting to the foul line. The 2015–16 team had its second lowest free throw rate under Roy Williams.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>