<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Features on Dadgum Box Scores</title>
    <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/categories/features/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Features on Dadgum Box Scores</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/categories/features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ACC Preseason Rankings</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/acc-preseason-rankings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/acc-preseason-rankings/</guid>
      <description>ACC Preseason Rankings Operation basketball is slated for October 23, so let&amp;rsquo;s explore how the preseason rankings line up with the end of the regular season. This is for team&amp;rsquo;s only, not for player preseason All-ACC teams.
Below is a chart comparing preseason rankings to end of regular season rankings in the conference since the start of the 2003-04 season. A few observations from exploring these rankings.
Carolina atop the rankings  Carolina has been selected as preseason number 1 six times (2007, 2008, 2009, 2010, 2012, 2016) The Tar Heels finished the regular season with league&amp;rsquo;s top ranking in five of those six years (hint: not 2010) Three times Carolina has finished the regular season atop the rankings despite being picked lower in the preseason (picked second in 2017, third in 2011, second in 2005)  Most frequent team picked first in the preseason  Duke: eight times The Blue Devils have been picked first in preseason eight times (2004, 2006, 2010, 2011, 2014, 2015, 2017, 2018) Duke has only finished first at the end of the regular season three times (2004, 2006, 2010)  Accuracy at the bottom?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Defense of Turnovers</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/in-defense-of-turnovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/in-defense-of-turnovers/</guid>
      <description>In Defense of Turnovers If you had to list out the bugaboos for the 2018 Tar Heels, defense should be on your list.
The facts are staggering:
 opponents shot 38 percent from behind the three-point line (worst in Roy Williams era) highest offensive points per possession (1.28) in a loss in Roy Williams era (Miami scored 1.32 PPP) 96.7 adjusted defensive efficiency (worst in Roy Williams era) five different opponents shot 50 percent or better from behind the three-point line a 50.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experienced Talent: Curious Continuity</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/continuity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/continuity/</guid>
      <description>Experienced Talent: Curious Continuity Prior to the start of the 2015-16 season, Roy Williams was asked about the challenges of getting an experienced team to grow as a group.
 Theres no question younger players can take bigger leaps, because they havent proven they can do it so you dont know if they can. I like an experienced team; they have been easier to coach. They understand those difficult moments in the locker room, they also understand those good moments in the locker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy Shot Volume Solver: Since &#39;03-04</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/esvs-since-03-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/esvs-since-03-04/</guid>
      <description>Easy Shot Volume Solver: Since &amp;lsquo;03-04  My offensive philosophy is that we’re going to run. We’re going to try to make the other team’s players run faster and longer than they ever have run in their lives &amp;hellip; because if I’m better than you are, the more possessions we play, the more likely it is that I’m going to beat you. If I play golf against Tiger Woods for one hole I might beat him, but over 18 holes, I have no chance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Defensive End in College Basketball</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/julius-frazier-peppers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/julius-frazier-peppers/</guid>
      <description>The Best Defensive End in College Basketball Julius Peppers enters his 17th NFL season next week. Before he became a NFL superstar, Peppers was a Tasamanian Devil of a two-sport athlete.
In the August 2001 issue of Sports Illustrated, Tim Crothers detailed the story of Peppers in a way only Crothers could do.
Peppers, a native of Bailey, N.C., was heavily recruited out of Southern Nash high school for both basketball and football.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>True or False: Freshmen</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/true-or-false-freshman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/true-or-false-freshman/</guid>
      <description>True or False: Freshmen True or False: Bobby Frasor is the only player in the Roy Williams era to start every game as a freshman.
True or False: Freshmen played a higher percentage of minutes during the 2005 Championship season than the 2009 or 2017 Championship seasons.
True or False: Nate Britt started more games as a freshman than Marvin Williams, Tony Bradley, and Danny Green combined.
True or False: A freshman has started at least one game in eight of 15 seasons in the Roy Williams era.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Retrospect, the 2017-18 Season</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/18-season-retrospect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/18-season-retrospect/</guid>
      <description>In Retrospect, the 2017-18 Season Fresh off the 2017 National Championship, North Carolina entered the 2017-18 season with a ton of uncertainty.
Carolina finished 26-11 overall, 11-7 in the ACC. The season ended in Charlotte in the second round of the NCAA Tournament.
A bit of perspective during the Roy Williams era.
After winning the 2005 National Championship, Carolina finished with a 23-8 record and its season ended in the second round of the NCAA Tournament.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duke &amp; Carolina: Early Entries</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/duke-carolina-early-entries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/duke-carolina-early-entries/</guid>
      <description>Duke &amp;amp; Carolina: NBA Early Entries Roy Williams was asked if the nature of the Duke-North Carolina rivalry has changed because of the frequent turnover of the players. Read his response below or listen to it here.
 It&amp;rsquo;s still the names of the front. You guys won&amp;rsquo;t believe this, but I think, strongly, we&amp;rsquo;ve had more guys leave early since I&amp;rsquo;ve been here than they have. Period. We just haven&amp;rsquo;t had the one-and-dones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carolina’s Frequent Fouler</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/carolinas-frequent-fouler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/carolinas-frequent-fouler/</guid>
      <description>Carolina’s Frequent Fouler Isaiah Hicks is one of the most puzzling UNC basketball players of all-time.
Because he can do things most collegiate players dream about, like putting opponents on a poster as seen here:
 But Hicks struggles to stay on the floor because he does a lot of this:
 Isaiah Hicks has committed four or more fouls in 31 of his last 70 career games. That’s 44 percent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Throw Rate since &#39;03-04</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/free-throw-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/free-throw-rate/</guid>
      <description>Where have all the free throws gone UNC looked the part of a National Champion for the majority of the 2015–16 season.
Last year’s squad had a higher adjusted offensive efficiency (123.3) and turnover rate (15.4) than both the 2005 and 2009 championship teams.
But where did the Tar Heels struggle?
A factor that gets overlooked is getting to the foul line. The 2015–16 team had its second lowest free throw rate under Roy Williams.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>