<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FYI | Dadgum Box Scores on Dadgum Box Scores</title>
    <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in FYI | Dadgum Box Scores on Dadgum Box Scores</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Factor Friday: Dec. 8, 2017</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-06/</guid>
      <description>Four Factor Friday: Dec. 8, 2017 TL;DR: The biggest reason for Carolina&amp;rsquo;s 9-1 start might be keeping opponents off the foul line and the offensive boards.
It&amp;rsquo;s the first edition of Four Factor Friday for the 2017-18 season, and let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at Carolina&amp;rsquo;s performance after the first 10 games.
Wait, what are the four factors?
The four factors determine why a team wins or loses. The factors are measured both on offense and defense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: Four factors, NBA draft picks, and more refs</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/update-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/update-02/</guid>
      <description>Update: Four factors, more refs, and NBA players Did you know UNC was 11-3 last season when posting a higher turnover percentage than its opponent?
It&amp;rsquo;s true, you can find that information here.
Two of those wins came in the NCAA Championship run against Butler and Kentucky. Carolina could win games turning the ball over more often than its opponent because of its strength in the other three factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carolina’s Frequent Fouler</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/carolinas-frequent-fouler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/carolinas-frequent-fouler/</guid>
      <description>Carolina’s Frequent Fouler Isaiah Hicks is one of the most puzzling UNC basketball players of all-time.
Because he can do things most collegiate players dream about, like putting opponents on a poster as seen here:
 But Hicks struggles to stay on the floor because he does a lot of this:
 Isaiah Hicks has committed four or more fouls in 31 of his last 70 career games. That’s 44 percent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: Referees, officials, zebras </title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/update-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/update-01/</guid>
      <description>Update: Referees, officials, zebras How often UNC has seen a certain referee this season?
I found myself asking this question when watching Carolina beat Florida State at home.
Rather than track it in a Excel or CSV file, it sparked me to use dadgumboxscores.com to organize and easily find this information.
So that’s what I did.
You can now find a list of officials for every game played in the 2016–17 UNC season here: http://dadgumboxscores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Factor Friday: Dec. 23, 2016</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-05/</guid>
      <description>Four Factor Friday: Dec. 23, 2016 In this edition of Four Factor Friday, we’re taking a look at the free throw rate of three UNC big men — Isaiah Hicks, Kennedy Meeks, and Tony Bradley.
What is free throw rate?
The more free throws a team attempts, the better opportunity it has to score and win games.
This is measured through a team’s free throw rate.
It’s the amount of free throw attempts divided by the amount of the field goal attempts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Factor Friday: Dec. 16, 2016</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-04/</guid>
      <description>Four Factor Friday: December 16, 2016 This article was originally published at The Secondary Break, run by Adrian Atkinson.
This edition of Four Factor Friday is centered around the showdown against Kentucky tomorrow. Let’s get into it.
When Kentucky has the ball  | | Kentucky | UNC | |:------:|:--------:|:----:| | eFG% | 53.6 | 44.8 | | TO% | 14.6 | 21.3 | | OR% | 39.6 | 29.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Factor Friday: Dec. 2, 2016</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-02/</guid>
      <description>Four Factor Friday: Dec. 2, 2016 The third addition of Four Factor Friday is specific. Since the Tar Heels only played 1 game in the last week, we’ll breakdown the loss to Indiana across all four factors:
 Effective field goal percentage Turnover percentage Offensive rebounding Free throw rate   eFG% Carolina posted a 44.3% offensive effective field goal percentage. The Tar Heels made 24 of 61 shots. Only 6 of those 24 shots were from behind the 3-point line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Factor Friday: Nov. 25, 2016</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-01/</guid>
      <description>Four Factor Friday: Nov. 25, 2016 In this edition of Four Factor Friday, we’ll take a closer look at how the Tar Heels are measuring up in offensive rebounding percentage.
OR% A team’s ability to increase its number of possessions, gives it a greater chance to score points and win games. Offensive rebounding is the main factor for a team to gain possessions.
It’s calculated by taking a team’s total offensive rebounds and comparing it to its opponents’ defensive rebounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Factor Friday: Nov. 18, 2016</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-00/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-00/</guid>
      <description>Four Factor Friday: Nov. 18, 2016   UNC is 3–0 and beating opponents by an average of 29 points.
 Effective field goal percentage Turnover percentage Offensive rebounding Free throw rate  Here’s how the Tar Heels are measuring up after 3 games in effective field goal percentage.
eFG% Effective field goal percentage takes into account that a 3-point field goal is worth more than a 2-point field goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Throw Rate since &#39;03-04</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/free-throw-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/free-throw-rate/</guid>
      <description>Where have all the free throws gone UNC looked the part of a National Champion for the majority of the 2015–16 season.
Last year’s squad had a higher adjusted offensive efficiency (123.3) and turnover rate (15.4) than both the 2005 and 2009 championship teams.
But where did the Tar Heels struggle?
A factor that gets overlooked is getting to the foul line. The 2015–16 team had its second lowest free throw rate under Roy Williams.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>