<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Updates on Dadgum Box Scores</title>
    <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/categories/updates/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Updates on Dadgum Box Scores</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/categories/updates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: Fouls, technicals, spreads</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/update-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/update-04/</guid>
      <description>Update: Fouls, Technicals, Spreads There are new pages added to the referee or officials section of the site:
 fouls - shows officials and total fouls game-by-game since &amp;lsquo;03-04
 technicals - shows any game with a technical foul (opponent or Carolina) in the Roy Williams era
 spread - shows the spread for all available games since &amp;lsquo;03-04, several games are unavailable
  This information is shared alongside the listed officials for each game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: Four factors game-by-game, better mobile access</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/update-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/update-03/</guid>
      <description>Update: Four factors for every game If you don&amp;rsquo;t know, the four factors explain why a team wins or loses. They&amp;rsquo;re the building blocks to efficiency. The four factors are:
 Shooting (eFG) Avoiding turnovers (TO%) Offensive rebounding (OR%) Getting to the foul line (FTRate)  I&amp;rsquo;ve now added four factors and points-per-possession (PPP) for every game since 2003-04 on this page on the site.
This was a tall task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: Four factors, NBA draft picks, and more refs</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/update-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/update-02/</guid>
      <description>Update: Four factors, more refs, and NBA players Did you know UNC was 11-3 last season when posting a higher turnover percentage than its opponent?
It&amp;rsquo;s true, you can find that information here.
Two of those wins came in the NCAA Championship run against Butler and Kentucky. Carolina could win games turning the ball over more often than its opponent because of its strength in the other three factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: Referees, officials, zebras </title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/update-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/update-01/</guid>
      <description>Update: Referees, officials, zebras How often UNC has seen a certain referee this season?
I found myself asking this question when watching Carolina beat Florida State at home.
Rather than track it in a Excel or CSV file, it sparked me to use dadgumboxscores.com to organize and easily find this information.
So that’s what I did.
You can now find a list of officials for every game played in the 2016–17 UNC season here: http://dadgumboxscores.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>