<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Dadgum Box Scores</title>
    <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Dadgum Box Scores</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ACC Preseason Rankings</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/acc-preseason-rankings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/acc-preseason-rankings/</guid>
      <description>ACC Preseason Rankings Operation basketball is slated for October 24, so let&amp;rsquo;s explore how the preseason rankings line up with the end of the regular season. This is for teams only, not for player preseason All-ACC teams.
Below is a chart comparing preseason rankings to end of regular season rankings in the conference since the start of the 2003-04 season. A few observations from exploring these rankings.
Carolina atop the rankings  Carolina has been selected as preseason number 1 six times (2007, 2008, 2009, 2010, 2012, 2016) The Tar Heels finished the regular season with league&amp;rsquo;s top ranking in five of those six years (hint: not 2010) Three times Carolina has finished the regular season atop the rankings despite being picked lower in the preseason (picked second in 2017, third in 2011, second in 2005)  Most frequent team picked first in the preseason  Duke: eight times The Blue Devils have been picked first in preseason eight times (2004, 2006, 2010, 2011, 2014, 2015, 2017, 2018) Duke has only finished first at the end of the regular season three times (2004, 2006, 2010)  Accuracy at the bottom?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Defense of Turnovers</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/in-defense-of-turnovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/in-defense-of-turnovers/</guid>
      <description>In Defense of Turnovers If you had to list out the bugaboos for the 2018 Tar Heels, defense should be on your list.
The facts are staggering:
 opponents shot 38 percent from behind the three-point line (worst in Roy Williams era) highest offensive points per possession (1.28) in a loss in Roy Williams era (Miami scored 1.32 PPP) 96.7 adjusted defensive efficiency (worst in Roy Williams era) five different opponents shot 50 percent or better from behind the three-point line a 50.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experienced Talent: Curious Continuity</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/continuity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/continuity/</guid>
      <description>Experienced Talent: Curious Continuity Prior to the start of the 2015-16 season, Roy Williams was asked about the challenges of getting an experienced team to grow as a group.
 Theres no question younger players can take bigger leaps, because they havent proven they can do it so you dont know if they can. I like an experienced team; they have been easier to coach. They understand those difficult moments in the locker room, they also understand those good moments in the locker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy Shot Volume Solver: Since &#39;03-04</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/esvs-since-03-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/esvs-since-03-04/</guid>
      <description>Easy Shot Volume Solver: Since &amp;lsquo;03-04  My offensive philosophy is that we’re going to run. We’re going to try to make the other team’s players run faster and longer than they ever have run in their lives &amp;hellip; because if I’m better than you are, the more possessions we play, the more likely it is that I’m going to beat you. If I play golf against Tiger Woods for one hole I might beat him, but over 18 holes, I have no chance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Defensive End in College Basketball</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/julius-frazier-peppers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/julius-frazier-peppers/</guid>
      <description>The Best Defensive End in College Basketball Julius Peppers enters his 17th NFL season next week. Before he became a NFL superstar, Peppers was a Tasamanian Devil of a two-sport athlete.
In the August 2001 issue of Sports Illustrated, Tim Crothers detailed the story of Peppers in a way only Crothers could do.
Peppers, a native of Bailey, N.C., was heavily recruited out of Southern Nash high school for both basketball and football.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: Fouls, technicals, spreads</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/update-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/update-04/</guid>
      <description>Update: Fouls, Technicals, Spreads There are new pages added to the referee or officials section of the site:
 fouls - shows officials and total fouls game-by-game since &amp;lsquo;03-04
 technicals - shows any game with a technical foul (opponent or Carolina) in the Roy Williams era
 spread - shows the spread for all available games since &amp;lsquo;03-04, several games are unavailable
  This information is shared alongside the listed officials for each game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>True or False: Freshmen</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/true-or-false-freshman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/true-or-false-freshman/</guid>
      <description>True or False: Freshmen True or False: Bobby Frasor is the only player in the Roy Williams era to start every game as a freshman.
True or False: Freshmen played a higher percentage of minutes during the 2005 Championship season than the 2009 or 2017 Championship seasons.
True or False: Nate Britt started more games as a freshman than Marvin Williams, Tony Bradley, and Danny Green combined.
True or False: A freshman has started at least one game in eight of 15 seasons in the Roy Williams era.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: Four factors game-by-game, better mobile access</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/update-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/update-03/</guid>
      <description>Update: Four factors for every game If you don&amp;rsquo;t know, the four factors explain why a team wins or loses. They&amp;rsquo;re the building blocks to efficiency. The four factors are:
 Shooting (eFG) Avoiding turnovers (TO%) Offensive rebounding (OR%) Getting to the foul line (FTRate)  I&amp;rsquo;ve now added four factors and points-per-possession (PPP) for every game since 2003-04 on this page on the site.
This was a tall task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Retrospect, the 2017-18 Season</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/18-season-retrospect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/18-season-retrospect/</guid>
      <description>In Retrospect, the 2017-18 Season Fresh off the 2017 National Championship, North Carolina entered the 2017-18 season with a ton of uncertainty.
Carolina finished 26-11 overall, 11-7 in the ACC. The season ended in Charlotte in the second round of the NCAA Tournament.
A bit of perspective during the Roy Williams era.
After winning the 2005 National Championship, Carolina finished with a 23-8 record and its season ended in the second round of the NCAA Tournament.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Factor Friday: Second Chance Points</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-07/</guid>
      <description>Four Factor Friday: Second Chance Points Goals change games. This is a old soccer cliche.
An obvious statement. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s true or not is up for debate, however, people have completed complex studies to confirm or deny it.
So what does this have to do with basketball?
Rebounds change games.
This is a belief of Roy Williams. It&amp;rsquo;s been a point of emphasis for all 15 of his Carolina teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duke &amp; Carolina: Early Entries</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/duke-carolina-early-entries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/duke-carolina-early-entries/</guid>
      <description>Duke &amp;amp; Carolina: NBA Early Entries Roy Williams was asked if the nature of the Duke-North Carolina rivalry has changed because of the frequent turnover of the players. Read his response below or listen to it here.
 It&amp;rsquo;s still the names of the front. You guys won&amp;rsquo;t believe this, but I think, strongly, we&amp;rsquo;ve had more guys leave early since I&amp;rsquo;ve been here than they have. Period. We just haven&amp;rsquo;t had the one-and-dones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Factor Friday: Dec. 8, 2017</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-06/</guid>
      <description>Four Factor Friday: Dec. 8, 2017 It&amp;rsquo;s the first edition of Four Factor Friday for the 2017-18 season, and let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at Carolina&amp;rsquo;s performance after the first 10 games.
Wait, what are the four factors?
The four factors determine why a team wins or loses. The factors are measured both on offense and defense.
 Shooting:: measured using effective field goal percentage, accounts for a 3-pointer being worth more than 2-pointer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: Four factors, NBA draft picks, and more refs</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/update-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/update-02/</guid>
      <description>Update: Four factors, more refs, and NBA players Did you know UNC was 11-3 last season when posting a higher turnover percentage than its opponent?
It&amp;rsquo;s true, you can find that information here.
Two of those wins came in the NCAA Championship run against Butler and Kentucky. Carolina could win games turning the ball over more often than its opponent because of its strength in the other three factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carolina’s Frequent Fouler</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/carolinas-frequent-fouler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/carolinas-frequent-fouler/</guid>
      <description>Carolina’s Frequent Fouler Isaiah Hicks is one of the most puzzling UNC basketball players of all-time.
Because he can do things most collegiate players dream about, like putting opponents on a poster as seen here:
 But Hicks struggles to stay on the floor because he does a lot of this:
 Isaiah Hicks has committed four or more fouls in 31 of his last 70 career games. That’s 44 percent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: Referees, officials, zebras </title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/update-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/update-01/</guid>
      <description>Update: Referees, officials, zebras How often UNC has seen a certain referee this season?
I found myself asking this question when watching Carolina beat Florida State at home.
Rather than track it in a Excel or CSV file, it sparked me to use dadgumboxscores.com to organize and easily find this information.
So that’s what I did.
You can now find a list of officials for every game played in the 2016–17 UNC season here: http://dadgumboxscores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Factor Friday: Dec. 23, 2016</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-05/</guid>
      <description>Four Factor Friday: Dec. 23, 2016 In this edition of Four Factor Friday, we’re taking a look at the free throw rate of three UNC big men — Isaiah Hicks, Kennedy Meeks, and Tony Bradley.
What is free throw rate?
The more free throws a team attempts, the better opportunity it has to score and win games.
This is measured through a team’s free throw rate.
It’s the amount of free throw attempts divided by the amount of the field goal attempts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Factor Friday: Dec. 16, 2016</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-04/</guid>
      <description>Four Factor Friday: December 16, 2016 This article was originally published at The Secondary Break, run by Adrian Atkinson.
This edition of Four Factor Friday is centered around the showdown against Kentucky tomorrow. Let’s get into it.
When Kentucky has the ball  | | Kentucky | UNC | |:------:|:--------:|:----:| | eFG% | 53.6 | 44.8 | | TO% | 14.6 | 21.3 | | OR% | 39.6 | 29.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Factor Friday: Nov. 25, 2016</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-01/</guid>
      <description>Four Factor Friday: Nov. 25, 2016 In this edition of Four Factor Friday, we’ll take a closer look at how the Tar Heels are measuring up in offensive rebounding percentage.
OR% A team’s ability to increase its number of possessions, gives it a greater chance to score points and win games. Offensive rebounding is the main factor for a team to gain possessions.
It’s calculated by taking a team’s total offensive rebounds and comparing it to its opponents’ defensive rebounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Factor Friday: Nov. 18, 2016</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-00/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/four-factor-friday-00/</guid>
      <description>Four Factor Friday: Nov. 18, 2016   UNC is 3–0 and beating opponents by an average of 29 points.
 Effective field goal percentage Turnover percentage Offensive rebounding Free throw rate  Here’s how the Tar Heels are measuring up after 3 games in effective field goal percentage.
eFG% Effective field goal percentage takes into account that a 3-point field goal is worth more than a 2-point field goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Throw Rate since &#39;03-04</title>
      <link>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/free-throw-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fyi.dadgumboxscores.com/free-throw-rate/</guid>
      <description>Where have all the free throws gone UNC looked the part of a National Champion for the majority of the 2015–16 season.
Last year’s squad had a higher adjusted offensive efficiency (123.3) and turnover rate (15.4) than both the 2005 and 2009 championship teams.
But where did the Tar Heels struggle?
A factor that gets overlooked is getting to the foul line. The 2015–16 team had its second lowest free throw rate under Roy Williams.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>